Guide to the Roland Herbert Bainton Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Notes/Source Materials, Series V
  - Topical sequence
    - Caspar Hedio (Box 40, Folder 577)
    - Historian's craft (Box 40, Folder 578)
    - History, philosophies of (Box 40, Folder 579,580)
    - Christoph Hoffman (Box 40, Folder 581)
    - The Horizon History of Christianity (Box 40, Folder 582-588)
    - John Hus (Box 40, Folder 589)
    - Investiture (Box 40, Folder 590)
    - Crusades (Box 40, Folder 590)
    - Japan (Box 40, Folder 591)
    - David Joris -Photostats of originals (Box 41, Folder 592-595)
    - David Joris -misc. notes (Box 42, Folder 596-598)
    - Left wing of the Reformation (Box 42, Folder 599)
    - Martin Luther -Bible/exegesis (Box 42, Folder 600)
    - Martin Luther -Catechism/ education (Box 42, Folder 601)
    - Martin Luther -Christmas (Box 42, Folder 602)
    - Martin Luther -Doctrinal (Box 42, Folder 603)
    - Martin Luther -Holl/ Schiel (Box 42, Folder 604)
    - Martin Luther -Indulgence controversy (Box 42, Folder 605)
    - Martin Luther -Letters of (Box 42, Folder 606)
    - Martin Luther -Lortz (Box 42, Folder 607)
    - Martin Luther -Lutheri imimicé defensoresque (Box 42, Folder 608)
    - Martin Luther -Marriage/ views of sex/ his parents (Box 43, Folder 609)
    - Martin Luther -Music (Box 43, Folder 610,611)
    - Martin Luther -Nüremberg Diets/ Fugger (Box 43, Folder 612)
    - Martin Luther -Passio Lutheri (Box 43, Folder 613)
    - Martin Luther -Political thought (Box 43, Folder 614)
    - Martin Luther -Primary works (Box 43, Folder 615)
    - Martin Luther -Problems (Box 43, Folder 616)
    - Martin Luther -Secondary sources (Box 43, Folder 617)
    - Martin Luther -Tischreden (Box 43, Folder 618)
    - Martin Luther -Various people (Box 43, Folder 619)
    - Martin Luther -Wittenberg Bervegung (Box 43, Folder 620)
    - Martin Luther -Worms some outlines (Box 43, Folder 621)
    - Martin Luther -misc. notes (Box 43, Folder 622-626)
    - Martin Luther -misc. notes (Box 44, Folder 627,628)
    - Martin Luther Christmas Book (Box 44, Folder 629,630)
    - Medieval Christianity and sex relations (Box 44, Folder 631)
    - Nationalists (Box 44, Folder 632)
    - Nineteenth century England (Box 44, Folder 633)
    - Nineteenth and twentieth centuries - general (Box 44, Folder 634)
    - Bernardino Ochino -Augsburg (Box 44, Folder 635)
    - Bernardino Ochino -Franciscan background (Box 44, Folder 636)
    - Bernardino Ochino -In Italy (Box 44, Folder 637)
    - Bernardino Ochino -Photostats from Sterling Library (Box 44, Folder 638)
    - Bernardino Ochino -Sermons in Italy/ replies in flight (Box 44, Folder 639)
    - Bernardino Ochino -misc. notes (Box 44, Folder 640)
    - Bernardino Ochino -misc. notes (Box 45, Folder 641-643)
    - Konrad Pellican (Box 45, Folder 644)
    - Poland (Box 45, Folder 645,646)
    - William Postell (Box 45, Folder 647)
    - Psychiatry/ Existentialism (Box 45, Folder 648)
    - Puritans (Box 45, Folder 649)
    - Reformation mystics (Box 45, Folder 650)
    - Reformation tracts (Box 45, Folder 651)
    - Religious liberty (Box 45, Folder 652)
    - Urbanus Rhegius (Box 45, Folder 653)
    - Rome, the fall of (Box 45, Folder 654)
    - Russian Church (Box 45, Folder 655)
    - Jakob Schenk (Box 45, Folder 656)
    - Michael Servetus -astrology/ syrups/ Fuchs (Box 45, Folder 657)
    - Michael Servetus -Bible (Box 45, Folder 658)
    - Michael Servetus -Blood circulation (Box 45, Folder 659)
    - Michael Servetus -De Trinitatio Erroribus/ Defensio (Box 45, Folder 660)
    - Michael Servetus -Documents: the trials of Vienne and Geneva (Box 45, Folder 661)
    - Michael Servetus -Early Church Trinitarian speculation (Box 45, Folder 662)
    - Michael Servetus -Geography (Box 46, Folder 663)
    - Michael Servetus -Gordon Alexander (Box 46, Folder 664)
    - Michael Servetus -Medieval Trinitarian speculation (Box 46, Folder 665)
    - Michael Servetus -Persons (Box 46, Folder 666)
    - Michael Servetus -Places (Box 46, Folder 667)
    - Michael Servetus -Restitutio (Box 46, Folder 668)
    - Michael Servetus -Tollin (Box 46, Folder 669)
    - Michael Servetus -misc. notes (Box 46, Folder 670,671)
    - Sex in the Early Church (Box 46, Folder 672)
    - Slavery (Box 46, Folder 673)
    - Spanish-Latin America (bibliography) (Box 46, Folder 674)
    - Spain (Box 46, Folder 675,676)
    - Towns in New England (Box 46, Folder 677)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Acontius (Box 46, Folder 678)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Authority (Box 46, Folder 398)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -France (Box 46, Folder 680)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Holland (Box 46, Folder 681)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Locke (Box 46, Folder 682)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Milton (Box 47, Folder 683)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Torquenada (Box 47, Folder 684)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -Roger Williams (Box 47, Folder 685)
    - The Travail of Religious Liberty -misc. notes (Box 47, Folder 686-689)
    - Ernst Troeltsch (Box 47, Folder 690)
    - War (Box 47, Folder 691)
    - William of Hesse (Box 47, Folder 692)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anna P. Absalon (Box 47, Folder 693)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anne of Cleve (Box 83, Folder 1169)
    - Women of the Reformation -Argula von Grumbach (Box 47, Folder 694)
    - Women of the Reformation -Associates (Box 48, Folder 695)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth and Marjory Bowes (Box 48, Folder 696)
    - Women of the Reformation -Brandenburg (Box 48, Folder 697)
    - Women of the Reformation -Isabella Bresegna (Box 48, Folder 698)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anne Boleyn/ Catherine of Aragon (Box 48, Folder 699)
    - Women of the Reformation -Catherine von Bora (Box 48, Folder 700)
    - Women of the Reformation -Catherine de Bourbon (Box 48, Folder 701)
    - Women of the Reformation -Caterina Cibo (Box 48, Folder 702)
    - Women of the Reformation -Climacus (Box 48, Folder 703)
    - Women of the Reformation -Vittoria Colonna (Box 48, Folder 704)
    - Women of the Reformation -Charlotte d'Albret (Box 48, Folder 705)
    - Women of the Reformation -Denmarka (Box 48, Folder 706)
    - Women of the Reformation -Eleanore de Roye (Box 48, Folder 707)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth I (Box 48, Folder 708,709)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth of Brandenburg/ Isabella (Box 48, Folder 710)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth of Brandenburg (Box 83, Folder 1170)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth of Braunschweig (Box 48, Folder 711)
    - Women of the Reformation -Elizabeth of Braunschweig (Box 83, Folder 1171-1172)
    - Women of the Reformation -England (Box 49, Folder 712)
    - Women of the Reformation -Renée de Ferrara (Box 49, Folder 713)
    - Women of the Reformation -Foxe (Box 49, Folder 714)
    - Women of the Reformation -Frederik II, Denmark (Box 49, Folder 715)
    - Women of the Reformation -Birgitte Gjoe (Box 49, Folder 716)
    - Women of the Reformation -Giulia Gonzaga (Box 49, Folder 717)
    - Women of the Reformation -Lady Jane Grey (Box 49, Folder 718)
    - Women of the Reformation -Handschriften problem (Box 49, Folder 719)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anna Hardenberg Frederick II/Queen Isabella (Box 49, Folder 720)
    - Women of the Reformation -Hungary (Box 49, Folder 721)
    - Women of the Reformation -Isabel de la Cruz (Box 49, Folder 722)
    - Women of the Reformation -Italy (Box 49, Folder 723)
    - Women of the Reformation -Katarina Jacgellonica (Box 49, Folder 724)
    - Women of the Reformation -Jeanne d'Albret/ Francois en Procession (Box 49, Folder 725)
    - Women of the Reformation -John Knox/ Scotland (Box 50, Folder 726)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anne Locke (Box 50, Folder 727)
    - Women of the Reformation -Louise de Colegny (Box 50, Folder 728)
    - Women of the Reformation -Marguerite de Navarre (Box 50, Folder 729)
    - Women of the Reformation -Maria of Hungary (Box 50, Folder 730)
    - Women of the Reformation -"Bloody" Mary (Box 50, Folder 731)
    - Women of the Reformation -Mary Queen of Scots (Box 50, Folder 732)
    - Women of the Reformation -Olympia Morata (Box 50, Folder 733)
    - Women of the Reformation -Parr (Box 50, Folder 734)
    - Women of the Reformation -Radziwill (Box 50, Folder 735)
    - Women of the Reformation -Rakow (Polish Arian settlement) (Box 50, Folder 736)
    - Women of the Reformation -Camillo Renato (Box 50, Folder 737)
    - Women of the Reformation -Wibrandis Rosenblatt (Box 51, Folder 738)
    - Women of the Reformation -Scandinavia/ Poland (Box 51, Folder 739)
    - Women of the Reformation -Sex and marriage (Box 51, Folder 740)
    - Women of the Reformation -Bona Sforza (Box 51, Folder 741)
    - Women of the Reformation -Spain (Box 51, Folder 742)
    - Women of the Reformation -Helen Stark (Box 51, Folder 743)
    - Women of the Reformation -Katherine Stubbs (Box 51, Folder 744)
    - Women of the Reformation -Teresa/ Sigea (Box 51, Folder 745)
    - Women of the Reformation -Anna Marchocka Teresy (Box 51, Folder 746)
    - Women of the Reformation -Ursula of Münsterberg (Box 51, Folder 747)
    - Women of the Reformation -Catherine Willoughby (Box 51, Folder 748)
    - Women of the Reformation -Isabella Zapolya (Box 52, Folder 749)
    - Women of the Reformation -Zell, Katherine (Box 52, Folder 750)
    - Women of the Reformation -Zell, Katherine (Box 83, Folder 1173-1175)
    - Women of the Reformation -misc. notes (Box 83, Folder 751-755)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Age of the Dreams (Box 83, Folder 756)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Amistad (Box 83, Folder 757)
    - Yale and the Ministry -B.W. Bacon (Box 52, Folder 758)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Leonard Bacon (Box 52, Folder 759)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Beechers (Box 52, Folder 760)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Charles R. Brown (Box 52, Folder 761)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Bushnell and geology (Box 52, Folder 762)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Education (Box 52, Folder 763)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Faculty dates (Box 52, Folder 764)
    - Yale and the Ministry -German influence (Box 52, Folder 765)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Jonathan Edwards and contemporaries (Box 52, Folder 766)
    - Yale and the Ministry -George Park Fisher (Box 52, Folder 767)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Letters (Box 52, Folder 768)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Library, 1742 (Box 52, Folder 769)
    - Yale and the Ministry -D.C. Macintosh (Box 52, Folder 770)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Mission (Box 52, Folder 771)
    - Yale and the Ministry -New England congregationalism (Box 52, Folder 772)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Frank C. Porter (Box 52, Folder 773)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Noah Porter (Box 52, Folder 774)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Slavery (Box 53, Folder 775)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Theologians (1860-1900) (Box 53, Folder 776)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Re. various people (Box 53, Folder 777,778)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Williston Walker (Box 53, Folder 779)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Yale (1750-1800) (Box 53, Folder 780)
    - Yale and the Ministry -Yale Divinity School (1858-1900) (Box 53, Folder 781)
    - Yale and the Ministry -misc. notes (Box 53, Folder 782,783)
    - Zwingli (Box 53, Folder 784)
    - Uncategorized notes (Box 53, Folder 785-790)
    - Uncategorized notes (Box 54, Folder 791-799)
    - Uncategorized notes (Box 85, Folder 10)
- Illustrations/Artwork, Series VI
  - Caricatures / sketches of individuals by Bainton
    - Adams, Harry (Box 55, Folder 800)
    - Adams, James Luther (Box 55, Folder 801)
    - Ahlstrom, Sydney (Box 55, Folder 802)
    - Alter, James (Box 55, Folder 803)
    - Archer, John Clark (Box 55, Folder 804)
    - Bacon, Benjamin (Box 55, Folder 805)
    - Bacon, Leonard (Box 55, Folder 806)
    - Bainton, J. Herbert (Box 55, Folder 807)
    - Bainton, Roland H. (Box 55, Folder 808)
    - Banner, William (Box 55, Folder 809)
    - Barth, Karl (Box 55, Folder 810)
    - Beach, Harlan P. (Box 55, Folder 811)
    - Beecher, Lyman (Box 55, Folder 812)
    - Brockway, Wallace (Box 55, Folder 813)
    - Brown, Charles R. (Box 55, Folder 814)
    - Burrows, Millar (Box 55, Folder 815)
    - Burton, Asa (Box 55, Folder 815a)
    - Bushnell, Horace (Box 55, Folder 816)
    - Cadbury, Henry J. (Box 55, Folder 817)
    - Calhoun, Robert L. (Box 55, Folder 818)
    - Campbell, J. Y. (Box 55, Folder 819)
    - Campenhausen, Hans (Box 55, Folder 820)
    - Carr, Aute (Box 55, Folder 821)
    - Castell (Box 55, Folder 822)
    - Christian, William (Box 55, Folder 823)
    - Craig, Tucker (Box 55, Folder 824)
    - Curtis, Edward L. (Box 55, Folder 825)
    - Dahl, Nils (Box 55, Folder 826)
    - Davis, Jerome (Box 55, Folder 827)
    - Day, George Edward (Box 55, Folder 828)
    - Dirks, Edward (Box 55, Folder 829)
    - Dittes, James (Box 55, Folder 830)
    - Dunham, William (Box 55, Folder 831)
    - Dwight, Timothy (Box 55, Folder 832)
    - Edwards, Jonathan (Box 55, Folder 833)
    - Emmons, Nathanael (Box 55, Folder 834)
    - Eusden, John (Box 55, Folder 835)
    - Fifield, James (Box 55, Folder 836)
    - Fisher, George Park (Box 55, Folder 837)
    - Fitch, Eleazar (Box 55, Folder 838)
    - Forman, Charles (Box 55, Folder 839)
    - Frei, Hans (Box 55, Folder 840)
    - Gatch (Box 55, Folder 841)
    - Gibbs, Willard (Box 55, Folder 842)
    - Gingerich, Melvin (Box 55, Folder 843)
    - Goodenough, Erwin (Box 55, Folder 844)
    - Goodrich, Chauncey A. (Box 55, Folder 845)
    - Greaves, Hubert (Box 55, Folder 846)
    - Gustafson, James (Box 55, Folder 847)
    - Harkness, Georgia (Box 55, Folder 848)
    - Harris, Samuel (Box 55, Folder 849)
    - Hartt, Julian (Box 55, Folder 850)
    - Hawes, Joel (Box 55, Folder 851)
    - Hein, Norvin (Box 55, Folder 852)
    - Hicks, Lansing (Box 55, Folder 853)
    - Hiers, Richard (Box 55, Folder 854)
    - Holborn, Hajo (Box 55, Folder 855)
    - Holmer, Paul (Box 55, Folder 856)
    - Hopkins, Samuel (Box 55, Folder 857)
    - Janson, H.W. (Box 55, Folder 858)
    - Johnson, Robert (Box 55, Folder 859)
    - Johnson, Samuel (Box 55, Folder 860)
    - Keller, Adolph (Box 55, Folder 861)
    - Kot, Stanislaw (Box 55, Folder 862)
    - Krahn, Cornelius (Box 55, Folder 863)
    - Latourette, Kenneth Scott (Box 55, Folder 864)
    - Lindbeck, George (Box 55, Folder 865)
    - Lovett, Sidney (Box 55, Folder 866)
    - Lowe (Box 55, Folder 867)
    - Luccock, Halford E. (Box 55, Folder 868)
    - Macintosh, Douglas Clyde (Box 55, Folder 869)
    - Muehl, William (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Meyer, Paul (Box 55, Folder 870)
    - Michaelson, Robert (Box 55, Folder 871)
    - Miller, Randolph C. (Box 55, Folder 872)
    - Minear, Paul (Box 55, Folder 873)
    - Moffatt, James (Box 55, Folder 874)
    - Morris, Raymond (Box 55, Folder 875)
    - Muehl, William (Box 55, Folder 876)
    - Napier, Davie (Box 55, Folder 877)
    - Nelson, John Oliver (Box 55, Folder 878)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard (Box 55, Folder 879)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 55, Folder 880)
    - Notestein, Wallace (Box 55, Folder 881)
    - Olson (Box 55, Folder 882)
    - Parsons (Box 55, Folder 883)
    - Pelikan, Jaroslav (Box 55, Folder 884)
    - Pierson, George (Box 55, Folder 885)
    - Pope, Liston (Box 55, Folder 886)
    - Porter, Frank C. (Box 55, Folder 887)
    - Rudin, Harry (Box 55, Folder 888)
    - Schroeder, John (Box 55, Folder 889)
    - Schubert, Paul (Box 56, Folder 890)
    - Seabury, Samuel (Box 56, Folder 891)
    - Seymour, Charles (Box 56, Folder 892)
    - Shedd, Clarence (Box 56, Folder 893)
    - Shrader, Leslie (Box 56, Folder 894)
    - Smith, Robert Seneca (Box 56, Folder 895)
    - Smith, Seymour (Box 56, Folder 896)
    - Sneath, E. Hershey (Box 56, Folder 897)
    - Stevens, George B. (Box 56, Folder 898)
    - Stiles, Ezra (Box 56, Folder 899)
    - Stuart, Moses (Box 56, Folder 900)
    - Taylor, Nathaniel W. (Box 56, Folder 901)
    - Tillich, Paul (Box 56, Folder 902)
    - Turner, Porter (Box 56, Folder 903)
    - Tweedy, Henry Hallam (Box 56, Folder 904)
    - Vieth, Paul (Box 56, Folder 905)
    - Walker, Williston (Box 56, Folder 906)
    - Weigle, Luther (Box 56, Folder 907)
    - Welch, Claude (Box 56, Folder 908)
    - Wheelock, Eleazar (Box 56, Folder 909)
    - Williams, Colin (Box 56, Folder 910)
    - Williams, Dan (Box 56, Folder 911)
    - Woolsey, Theodore Dwight (Box 56, Folder 912)
    - Wood, Ray (Box 56, Folder 913)
    - Wright, Henry B. (Box 56, Folder 914)
    - Zeckhauser (Box 56, Folder 915)
    - More than one caricature on page (Box 56, Folder 916)
    - Unidentified caricatures (Box 56, Folder 917)
    - Nils Dahl and Paul Holmer (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - "Taylor Lectures 1978" (Box 86, Folder 86)
  - Other illustrations and artwork by Bainton
    The Yale Arts Library holds a collection of watercolors by Bainton of students in Sterling Memorial library. See: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/8203031
    - African safari drawings / watercolors: gift of Susan Pinco (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Watercolor of recreational activities: gift of Herbert Pifer, 1949 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Related to Holden Village (Box 56, Folder 918)
    - Related to Yale Divinity School (Box 56, Folder 919)
    - Other artwork (Box 56, Folder 920)
    - Related to YDS production of The Mikado (watercolors by RHB and slides) (Box 56, Folder 921)
    - Additional artwork, incl. characters in H.M.S. Pinafore (YDS production), Sterling Memorial Library courtyard, outdoor market in Poland, 1952, 1977, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook containing tracings of cartoons from various magazines - "The Church in Caricature - Late 19th and early 20th centuries" (Box OV1)
  - Illustrations of Bainton
    - Caricatures and sketches of Bainton by others (Box 56, Folder 922)
  - Illustrations for Bainton books
    - Behold the Christ (Box 56, Folder 923-927)
    - Christendom (Box 57, Folder 928-932)
    - Christian Attitudes Toward War and Peace (Box 57, Folder 933)
    - Church of Our Fathers (Box 57, Folder 934-937)
    - Church of Our Fathers (Box 58, Folder 938-943)
    - Erasmus of Christendom (Box 58, Folder 944-948)
    - Erasmus of Christendom (Box 59, Folder 949-950)
    - Here I Stand (Box 59, Folder 951-958)
    - Here I Stand (Box 60, Folder 959-963)
    - The Horizon History of Christianity (Box 60, Folder 964-970)
    - Luther's Meditations on the Gospels (Box 60, Folder 971)
    - Pilgrim Parson (Box 60, Folder 972)
    - The Reformation of the Sixteenth Century (Box 60, Folder 973)
    - The Reformation of the Sixteenth Century (Box 61, Folder 974)
    - Roly: Chronicle of a Stubborn Non-Conformist (Box 61, Folder 975-976)
    - Women of the Reformation (Box 61, Folder 977-983)
    - Women of the Reformation (Box 62, Folder 984-985)
    - Yale and the Ministry (Box 62, Folder 986)
  - Topical Sequence of Illustrations
    - American (Box 62, Folder 987)
    - Baptism / Temptation (Box 62, Folder 988)
    - Caricatures by Thelma Hansen (Box 62, Folder 989)
    - Caricature of an Arian (Socinian) (Box 62, Folder 990)
    - Sebastian Castellio (Box 62, Folder 991)
    - Cathedrals of England ( National Geographic issue) (Box 62, Folder 992)
    - Celtic art (Box 62, Folder 993)
    - Christ (symbols) (Box 62, Folder 994)
    - Christmas (Box 62, Folder 995)
    - The Church in caricature (late 19th early 20th centuries) (Box 62, Folder 996)
    - Churches in India (Box 63, Folder 997)
    - Churches of Sweden (Box 63, Folder 998)
    - Coins (Box 63, Folder 999)
    - Coptic Art (Box 63, Folder 1000)
    - Crucifixion (Box 63, Folder 1001)
    - Deposition (Box 63, Folder 1002)
    - Donation of Constantine (Box 63, Folder 1003)
    - Early Church (Box 63, Folder 1004)
    - Eighteenth century (Box 63, Folder 1005)
    - England (Box 63, Folder 1006,1007)
    - Footwashing / Cleansing Temple (Box 63, Folder 1008)
    - Gethsemane (Box 63, Folder 1009)
    - Golden Remains of John Hales (Box 63, Folder 1010)
    - Some heretics / Calvin (Box 63, Folder 1011)
    - Illustrations from rare book catalogues (Box 63, Folder 1012)
    - Initials and drawings - some from Schramm (Box 64, Folder 1013)
    - Judgment / Pantocrator (Box 64, Folder 1014)
    - Last Supper / Palm Sunday (Box 64, Folder 1015)
    - Line Drawings by RHB (Box 64)
    - Line drawings by RHB for unidentified books (Box 64, Folder 1016,1017)
    - Luther / Charles V (Box 64, Folder 1018)
    - Lutheran churches in America (early) (Box 64, Folder 1019)
    - Martin Luther film (Box 64, Folder 1020)
    - Medieval (Box 64, Folder 1021-1024)
    - Methodism (Box 64, Folder 1025)
    - Miracles / Parables (Box 65, Folder 1026)
    - Music in the Middle Ages (Box 65, Folder 1027)
    - Music in the Middle Ages
    - Nativity / Madonna and child (Box 65, Folder 1028-1030)
    - Postcards (Box 65, Folder 1031-1033)
    - Poster art in World War I (Box 65, Folder 1034)
    - Prints for unidentified books (Box 65, Folder 1035)
    - Puritans (Box 65, Folder 1036)
    - Reformation (Box 65, Folder 1037)
    - Resurrection (Box 65, Folder 1038)
    - St. Bartholomew's Day / Joachin Prophecy (Box 66, Folder 1039)
    - Caspar Schwenkfeld (Box 66, Folder 1040)
    - M. Servetus (Box 66, Folder 1041)
    - Sixteenth century figure (unidentified: portrait hung in RHB's office) (Box 66, Folder 1042)
    - Sixteenth century woodcuts (Box 66, Folder 1043,1044)
    - Sixteenth century - incl. French Wars of Religion (Box 66, Folder 1045)
    - Sixteenth century - incl. Thomas More (Box 66, Folder 1046)
    - Trail of Blood (Box 66, Folder 1047)
    - Trinity (Box 66, Folder 1048)
    - Veronica, Saint (Box 66, Folder 1049)
    - Wartburg Castle (Box 66, Folder 1050)
    - Woodcuts in Monographien zur deutschen Kulturgeschichte XII. Band: Der evangelische Geistliche (1905) (Box 66, Folder 1051)
    - Woodcuts in Monographien zur deutschen Kulturgeschichte X. Band: Fahrende Leute (1902) (Box 66, Folder 1052)
    - Miscellaneous negatives - RHB list of contents included (Box 66, Folder 1053)
    - Miscellaneous negatives - RHB list of contents included (Box 67, Folder 1054-1065)
    - Miscellaneous illustrations (Box 67, Folder 1066-1069)
  - Slides
    - Calvin; Catholic 18th century; Methodist 19th century; Chinese and Japanese artwork of Biblical stories; Early American; Early Church; Elizabeth of Hungary; Johann Hus/Czech history; Luther; Lutherans in Holland; Medieval Church; Netherlands;Presbyterians (Box 68, Folder 1070)
    - Pilgrims England; Russian, Rumanian, etc; Sixteenth century; The Virgin Mary/ Christ; Wyclif/ Edwin; miscellaneous persons, places, things (Box 69, Folder 1071)
- Collected Material, Series VII
  - Bibliographies by others, regarding:
    - The Reformation; Medieval Church (Box 70, Folder 1072)
    - Social issues and religion (Box 70, Folder 1073)
    - Women's history (Box 70, Folder 1074)
    - American church history (Box 70, Folder 1075)
    - Christian theology since Schleiermacher (Box 70, Folder 1076)
    - Modern European history (Box 70, Folder 1077)
  - Writings by others
    - Beauchamp, Virginia Walcott: "Women in the Reformation: Directions for Research" (Box 70, Folder 1078)
    - Bense, Walter: "The Just War in the Sixteenth Century", n.d. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Bense, Walter: "Noel Beda - Missing Link between Calvinism and Medieval Augustinianism?", 1968 (Box 70, Folder 1078)
    - Cast, David: re. Marten van Heemskerck, n.d. (Box 70, Folder 1078)
    - Cook, Robert M.: "The United States and Vietnam", 1966 (Box 70, Folder 1078)
    - Forest, James H.: Survey of the World Council of Churches Consultation on Disarmament, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 1078)
    - Garside, Charles, Jr.: "The Origins of Calvin's Theology of Music: 1536-1543", 1977 (Box 70, Folder 1079)